coleparmer.com 2019-10-17

# Privacy Policy from Cole-Parmer

This is the web site of Cole-Parmer. We can be reached via e-mail at [sales@coleparmer.com](mailto:sales@coleparmer.com). Outside the US, please contact your local office.

## Secure Shopping

At Cole-Parmer, we understand your concerns about online security and privacy. All orders on our site are encrypted using Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology. SSL is a complex form of cryptography that makes it virtually impossible for a third party to decrypt any useful information you provide. You can use our site knowing that your personal and credit card information is protected when transmitted online. Cole-Parmer uses GoDaddy website security services, allowing you to place Internet orders with confidence, knowing that your credit card information will be secure.

## What Information Do We Collect?

When you visit Cole-Parmer, we’ll be collecting various types of information from you. If you place an order from our site, we’ll need to collect your shipping and billing information. Cole-Parmer will also be collecting data from all site visitors such as IP name, domain name, web page, length of time spent at the site and pages accessed while visiting the site, but not the e-mail address. We collect the e-mail address of visitors only via information volunteered by you, such as survey information, catalog requests, and/or site registrations. This information is collected for statistical purposes and to help with the administration and improvement of the site. Cole-Parmer also reserves the right to retain the content of any questions or comments that are sent to our employees. This information will be used to help improve responses to future questions. For international customers, information may be shared with our international dealers. See our full cookie disclosure.

## What is this Information Used For?

The information that Cole-Parmer collects is used to better serve our customers. This information is used to notify you of changes made to our site, to tell you about new products available on our site, and to contact you for other legitimate business purposes. From time to time, we may choose to exchange this information with other parties whose products and/or services we think may be of interest to you. If you do not want your information being exchanged with other parties, send us an e-mail at [sales@coleparmer.com](mailto:sales@coleparmer.com) from each e-mail address that you’ve used to request information, register, or place an order on Cole-Parmer. Outside the US, please contact your local office. Customers who supply us with their telephone numbers online may receive telephone contact from us with information regarding orders they have placed online. Please provide us with your correct phone number.

## Disclosures Regarding Use of Google Features

Cole-Parmer uses certain Google Analytics features for Display Advertising (e.g., Remarketing, Google Display Network Impression Reporting, DoubleClick Campaign Manager Integration or Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting). This allows Cole-Parmer to collect Non-Personally Identifiable Information about your visits to our website, and your interaction with our products and services. No Personally Identifiable Information is collected during in this process. You can opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customize Google Display Network ads, by using the [Google Ads Settings](https://www.google.com/settings/ads?hl=en&sig=ACi0TCgQgzHNd4KNY48hlC_kdZBWGDJNu1DZfRXQ0LtGKKKhcSIrRVyKhQ7Og_9OCn1otEqtT9FCMGFPzmvxlaWA4YZ77pDC3Q). You may find Google Analytics’ currently available opt-outs for the web at https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/. Cole-Parmer uses Remarketing with Google Analytics to advertise online. Remarketing allows Cole-Parmer to follow up with those who have already visited our website, and deliver ad content specifically targeted to the interests they expressed during those previous visits. Third-party vendors, including Google, may show Cole-Parmer’s ads on sites across the Internet. Cole-Parmer and third-party vendors, including Google, use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookie) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) together to (i) inform, optimize, and serve ads based on our website users’ past visits to our website and (ii) report how our ad impressions, other uses of ad services and interactions with these ad impressions and ad services are related to visits to our site.

## Mobile Apps

Some services provided by Cole-Parmer include the use of mobile apps created by or for Cole-Parmer. These apps have the same privacy policy as this website, except where otherwise noted. These apps may ask to use your device’s location services to provide you with location-based features such as local environmental conditions or location data in reports. They may also request additional permissions such as access to your device’s camera or local storage. These permissions allow our apps to enable use of all features, such as adding images to data reports or saving/sharing them for later reference. If desired, these permissions can be disabled by the user in most modern platforms, though this may affect app functionality. Android apps also use Google Play Services, a third-party set of features provided by Google which has [its own privacy policy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/). Questions or comments regarding our mobile apps can be directed to [mobilesupport@coleparmer.com](mailto:mobilesupport@coleparmer.com).

## How do I Unsubscribe?

Visitors to our Web site can opt-out from receiving e-mail updates and advertisements by unchecking the box next to any or all e-mail types listed on our E-mail Preferences page. Please be sure to enter the e-mail address(s) used to sign-up or when requesting other information from us. If you decide you no longer want to receive any e-mails regarding special offers, product, service and technical information; you can unsubscribe from the footer of the e-mail itself or visit our unsubscribe page.

If you supply us with your postal address online, you may receive periodic mailings from us with information on new products and services, or upcoming events. If you do not wish to receive such mailings, please let us know by e-mail at [sales@coleparmer.com](mailto:sales@coleparmer.com). Outside the US, please contact your local office. Please provide us with your exact name and address.
